David Goldstein

1 (617) 543-0274 | <u>Dgoldstein01@gmail.com</u> 1833 New Hampshire Avenue NW #116, Washington, DC 20009

Aim and Intent

I am driven by problem solving. From writing policy, researching, and learning languages, to writing code and developing applications, I seek to understand why systems work, what their effects are, and how I can change them to receive the desired outcome. I am energized by projects and teams that ask these questions and then draw from diverse skillsets and disciplines to find the answer.

Education

• Macalester College, St. Paul, MN | Bachelor of Arts, GPA: 3.80

Fall 2012 - Spring 2016

- o <u>Majors</u>: Computer Science, International Studies, and Arabic Language
- o Concentration: Middle East and Islamic Studies

American University of Sharjah, UAE

Fall 2014

Boren National Security Program, Morocco

Summer 2013

• National Security Language Initiative, Morocco

Summer 2012

Professional Experience

• Defense Intelligence Agency, UDIP | Program Assistant, Washington, DC

Fall 2016 - Present

- O Assist in development of DIA analytic products.
- O Relate analysis tradecraft in creating software tools.
- O Research and write on issues in the Middle East.

• Karam Law | Paralegal, Bloomington, MN

2015 -2016

- o Drafted legal briefs based on intensive research and careful preparation.
- O Prepared and organized client files and court filings.
- o Translated and interpreted official Arabic and French documents.

Department of State, PRM/Office of Asia and the Near East | Intern, Washington, DC

Summer 2015

- O Researched and reported on Middle East security issues.
- O Drafted, edited, and cleared official papers and statements.
- O Assisted senior-level officials in a fast-paced environment on a variety of projects.

Minnesota International Center | Intern, Minneapolis, MN

Summer 2013

- O Maintained and updated company and donor databases.
- O Created interactive online world map using Google Maps API.
- o Arranged meeting with State Department officials and international visitors.

Advocates for Human Rights | Volunteer, Minneapolis, MN

2013 - 2016

- O Prepared and organized official documents for use in court.
- o Coordinated with attorneys and clients throughout the legal process.
- O Analyzed, translated, and interpreted documents in Arabic and French.

Professional Interests

- Big Data Analytics
- Machine Learning
- Defensive Cyber
- Application Design and Development
- US Cyber Policy
- International Law
- Middle East Politics
- Arabic and French Language

Fellowships and Awards

- Council of American Ambassadors Fellow, 2015
- Clinton Global Initiative Fellow, 2013
- Boren National Security Fellow, 2013
- Dean's List, 2012-2016
- National Security Language Initiative Fellow, 2012

Skills and Language Proficiency

- Java, C++, C, Python
- Perl, JavaScript, BASH
- Arabic 2/2
- French 2+/2+
- Hebrew 1+/1+

Coding and Application Development

- "Parsing and Compiling Data from Securities and Exchange Commission Database" Independent Project, 2016
- "Secure Encryption/Decryption Chat Program" Macalester College, 2016
- "Mapping English Synonyms: A Synonym Scraper" Independent Project, 2016
- "Adaptive Flash Cards: An Arabic Language Learning Tool" Independent Project, 2013
- "Kitchen Sync: An Android Application for the Macalester Cafeteria" Macalester College, 2013
- "Analysis of Time Complexity in Sudoku Puzzle Solutions" Independent Project, 2012

Opinion and Political Analysis

- "Lessons Learned from the Iraqi Criminal Tribunal: A Case for Syria" Macalester College, 2015
- "The Carrot or the Stick: Kurdistan, Iraq, and the US Intervention in Anfal" American University of Sharjah, 2014
- "Guantanamo and the Global War on Terror: Emerging Paradigms in International Law" Macalester College, 2014
- "Is Israel's Stuxnet Attack on Iran an Act of Aggression Under International Law?" Macalester College, 2014
- "Legal Analysis of the 2013 Chinese Cyber Attacks on the New York Times" Macalester College, 2013
- "Political and Legal Analysis of Israel's Sea Blockade of Gaza Port" Macalester College, 2013

Academic Research

- "Demographic Impacts of Syrian Refugees in Lebanon: Looking Forward" Macalester College, 2016
- "Implementation and Analysis of Artificial Intelligence in Card Games" Macalester College, 2015
- "Analysis of CPU Speed When Compared with L Cache Size" Macalester College, 2015
- "Translation and Commentary on) اربعة ملايين لاجىء -الانفجار السكاني- هل تبقى سورية؟ وهل ينجو لبنان؟ (Four Million Refugees, the Demographic Bomb: Will Syria survive? Will Lebanon Remain?)" Macalester College, 2015
- "Analysis of Time Complexity in RSA Encryption-Decryption Methods" American University of Sharjah, 2014

References

Andrew Overman
Department Chair
Macalester College Classics
overman@macalester.edu
651-696-6375

Monique Ramgoolie

Deputy Director

Department of State PRM/ANE

ramgooliem@state.gov

617-423-2254

Leslie Karam Attorney and Owner Karam Law leslie@karamlaw.com 612-600-5077 ext. 557